we make tall grass short.
My biggest constraint is people.
When I hire experienced technicians,
they aren't always a culture fit.
And when I hire culture fits that aren't experienced,
we've been unsuccessful in training them.
How hard is this to train?
We train them, they show us they can do the work.
And then when they're on their own,
the quality falls apart.
What are the complaints about that they just like
literally cut corners, quite literally,
or don't cut corners?
Correct.
Yeah, the short grass that we're supposed to make
is still long.
Yeah, got it.
Rules without enforcement are not rules,
they're suggestions.
It's like, you have to protect the business.
And the thing that you have to protect most
is the reputation.
But if you allow people who cut corners
and you don't publicly give kudos to people
who are consistent, and you don't punish or remove
the people who are not,
you basically reinforce that it is okay to cut corners.
You have to define exactly what you want
into observable terms.
You have to demonstrate it in front of them,
get them to actually do it.
And then you have to see what they did.
And then you have to immediately correct
the people who fuck up.
You have to give kudos to the people who do it well,
and you have to keep repeating it until it sticks.
And then you'll move on to reinforcing people
for giving kudos to each other.
And as soon as they start giving kudos
to each other in public,
that is when you'll know that you'll start
to have built the culture.
And then after that, what ends up happening
is they start punishing each other in private,
meaning they say, hey man, you fucked that up,
don't let him see that.
It's gonna get all of us in trouble.